Nathaniel Medrano

Full Stack Developer

Full Stack developer with a well-rounded experience in LAMP stack development. My focus lies in challenging projects that will sharpen my skills and hone in my drive to create applications that people will love to use. I consistently aim to gain a solid understanding of a project's requirements and what functionality the end user needs to create a well polished and scalable application.

Experience

2017-05 - Freelance Full Stack Developer

present

Nathaniel-David Web Development

Housing Authority of the City of Austin - Consulting and development contract to create a custom platform that optimizes the reporting, tracking, and processing performance of all four departments within the organization.

- Responsibilities: Consulting, wire-framing, design, database schema, and development
- Project Specs: Laravel 5.5, VueJS, MySQL/SQL Server Databases, Active Directory

Ascension Dental Partners - Created multiple custom platforms for both internal and customer use. Projects included a reporting site for both admin and dental providers, custom Wordpress checkouts for membermouse products, and a multi-tenant platform for dental providers that included registration, customization of fee schedules, branding, checkout, and a Member/Admin dashboard.

- Responsibilities: Wire-framing, design, database schema, server configuration/migration, development, and launch
- Project Specs: Laravel 5.1 & 5.4, Wordpress, Membermouse, remote MySQL DBs, Ubuntu servers, Stripe Checkout

Charmed Labs (pixycam.com) - Wordpress site for product information/documentation and full migration of RedMine forum to Discourse platform

- Responsibilities: Server configuration, db migration, Wordpress setup, and DocuWiki installation
- Project Specs: Ubuntu 16.04, custom Ruby database migration script, Wordpress, and Discourse

2016-03 -

Full Stack Developer

2017-05 SixPack Shortcuts

Overview - Contributed to the member site functionality for AWS push notifications, product tracking, and admin reporting. Was the primary developer for Affiliate management, Sales Funnels, and split testing.

- Responsibilities Collaborate with marketing and affiliate management teams; create sales funnels and split tests; create new products (SalesForce/Shopify/Database/Landing Page);
- Project Specs Laravel 4, Shopify, AWS, Salesforce Products, Has Offers, Maripost, and Stripe

2014-10 -2016-03

Web Developer

Sage Environmental Consulting

Built custom web apps for internal and marketing use with Laravel, AngularJS, and WordPress. Handled tickets from clients and department heads to update sites and keep projects up to date. Projects included:

- SageAquaticLab.com Content site for the Oklahoma Aquatic Laboratory. Bootstrap site that allows for web and mobile optimization
- ArchiveManager DB Lookup Laravel App that runs email queries for marketing to retrieve and filter information that directly helps with revenue for the annual 4C Marketplace conference

Education

2014-02 - Codeup

2014-04

Enhanced my knowledge of LAMP Stack as well as html/css and JavaScript. Projects included use of Phone Gap, Angular JS, JQuery, as well as MVC Frameworks such as Laravel and Ionic.

References

Andrea Galloway, HACA, MIS Director, 512.477.4488 ext 2248

Eric Johnson, Ascension Dental, CEO, 214.505.9352

Personal Info

Address

358 Broome St New York, NY 10013

Phone

210.367.3596

E-mail

me@nathaniel-david.com

www

https://nathaniel-david.com

GitHub

https://github.com/Nathaniel-David

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathaniel medrano/

Skills

Laravel

PHP

JS/JQuery

MySQL

CSS/Bootstrap

Wordpress

Stripe API

Ubuntu

Apache/NGINX

Flutter/Dart